chemistwarehouse.com.au 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy | Chemist Warehouse

#### **CWH respects your privacy**

Thank you for visiting the ChemistWarehouse.com.au Web site.

**ChemistWarehouse.com.au** is a leading online pharmacy and retail store for pharmaceutical products, owned and operated in Australia under ePharmacy Group Pty Ltd.

The owners of **ChemistWarehouse.com.au** , its subsidiaries, related entities and affiliates (" **ChemistWarehouse.com.au** ", " **we** ", " **us** ", " **our** ") respect your privacy and we are committed to comply with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (" **Act** "), the Act's Australian Privacy Principals (" **APP** ") and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679. In addition, we are bound by and committed to the privacy of health records as contained in Health Legislation in every state.

We respect your right to privacy and are committed to providing clear and honest information to explain how we use the information you give us. We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains the types of personal information we collect, how we use that information, who we share it with, and how we protect that information.

This policy (together with our [terms and conditions]() sets out the basis on which any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our practices regarding your personal information, and how we will treat it. By continuing to use this website, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

#### **Information Covered by This Policy**

This policy covers all personal information collected and used by chemistwarehouse.com.au. In this policy, “personal information” means information or pieces of information that could identify you. This includes information such as your name, address, username, or email address, but could also include information such as your IP address, or information about your preferences and shopping habits.

If you have any questions, queries or complaints, please contact us on [info@chemistwarehouse.com.au](mailto:info@chemistwarehouse.com.au) or mail us at

**Chemist Warehouse Customer Service**

Building F, 44 Raglan St

Preston VIC 3072

Australia

### **The key principles of our privacy policy are as follows.**

  1. _We use your personal information to allow us to provide the services you ask us for._
  2. _We will only share your information with other companies if this is necessary to provide our service to you (for example, to deliver medication or products we will need to share your address with a postal service). We share the minimum amount of information for the relevant purpose. Those we share your information with are not allowed to use it to try to sell their own services to you._
  3. _We do not sell, provide, or allow your Information to be viewed by any person not engaged or employed by us without your prior consent._
  4. _We will only send you information about our own products and services and those of group companies and selected partners if you have given us permission to. Bear in mind that if you choose not to receive this information, you may miss out on offers and deals._
  5. _In some instances (for example, customers using any kind of medicines regardless of prescription only medicines), we will need to collect sensitive information about your health – such as existing health conditions or prescribed medication. The law and Australian health regulations set out how we can record and use this sensitive information._

#### This privacy policy sets out:

  1. _how and why we collect and use your personal information._
  2. _how we use this information and to whom the information may be disclosed._
  3. _our commitment to respecting and protecting the privacy of people who use our website and our services._

Please read this privacy policy carefully. By using our website and services you are confirming that you agree to the terms of this privacy policy. If you do not agree to this privacy policy, do not use our website or services.

We may from time to time make changes to this privacy policy. We will set out any important changes at the end of the latest version of the privacy policy. If there are substantial changes, we will also explain the changes in the summary at the start of this policy. You should check this privacy policy regularly to see if there have been any changes.

#### What personal information we collect and how we use it

#### Providing you with goods and services

We collect personal information from you in a number of ways, mainly when you buy goods or services and from the way you use our website. This personal information will include your name, date of birth, delivery and billings address, email address and phone numbers. We will use this personal information to help us meet your order; deliver the goods and services to you and to give you the information you need to track your order.

In some cases, for example if you are ordering pharmacy-only medicines from us, we will ask you for extra information to make sure that our pharmacists can check the medicine is suitable for you. This will mean collecting information about your health, including medical information.

#### Additional data required for medication purchases

If you want to purchase any medications we will need to know whether you pay full price for your prescriptions or if they are government subsidized. We will also collect information about your existing medical conditions and any medication your doctor has prescribed for you, gender, DOB, address, Medicare details depends on type of medications purchased. We will use this information to look after your health and comply with Pharmacy Law. This may mean we have to contact you in certain circumstances that are relevant to your ongoing care (for example, sending you reminders about repeat prescriptions). For more information about what information we may collect in such when providing prescriptions please read our [prescription service](https://www.chemistwarehouse.com.au/AboutUs/Prescriptions) page

#### Getting to know you better

We will collect and store details of all medicines and other products we supply to you, and also medicines that you may have from us on repeat prescription. We also collect information about our customers and prospective customers from other organisations, such as marketing agencies. We use this information to help us get to know you better and to enable us to provide better service.

We will use this information, as well as the other information we collect about you, to improve the quality of our website, as well as improving the personal information we hold about you. This helps us to understand you, so we can send you marketing messages that should be relevant to you (unless you have told us that you do not to want to receive marketing from us). We will also put this information (which does not identify you) with other information so that we can use all the information we have to help us understand our customers and prospective customers better, including helping to predict which of our services may be of interest to them. We may share your information with our marketing service providers to help us identify prospective customers.

Please note that we will only send you marketing information about our own products and services and those of our group companies and selected partners, if you have given us permission to do so (you have to tell us if you want us to send you marketing information). We will not sell your information to anyone else, for any reason. You can opt out of remarketing services by visiting <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>.

#### Our service providers

_Sometimes we use other organisations (service providers) to help us provide our services and improve them, including:_

  1. _delivering your orders and providing emails or texts so you can track your order;_
  2. _sending letters and marketing material;_
  3. _carrying out market research; and_
  4. _helping us to analyse anonymous information about customers._

Where we need to share information with our service providers, we give them only the minimum amount they need to provide services to us and you. Those we share your information with are not allowed to use it to try to sell their own services to you. They are all bound by privacy policies that at a minimum mirror ours.

#### information we receive and collect from other sources:

We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate (for example a website for another Chemist Warehouse brand) or the other services we provide. We also work closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, analytics providers, search information providers, and credit reference agencies) and may receive information about you from them. We use Google Analytics as a partner to collect data. You can find more information about these services here: [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners). We may also collect information about you from publicly available sources, including publically available content on social media, always with the aim of improving your service to you.

#### When using our website

We may collect information about you as you are using our website, such as information about your browser, your location, the country you are visiting from, your IP address, which areas of our website you visit and what links you click on etc. We may use the information we collect about you, after making it anonymous, to create statistics which we then share with others including ad networks, search engines and providers of analysis services.

All the personal information we collect about you is stored by us or by our service providers on our behalf in a legally compliant manner, consistent with industry best practice.

#### Marketing

By agreeing to our privacy policy you are agreeing to allow us to contact you about products and services which we, our group companies and selected partners provide and think you would be interested in, and to let you know about relevant offers and news. Chemist Warehouse will share the data provided by you to third parties (as disclosed in our Cookie Policy) in order to communicate to you via our various marketing channels, analyze behavior on our website and understand your data.

If you no longer want to receive marketing information in a particular way, or receive any marketing at all, you can change your mind at any time. You can change your preferences by contacting us via email at info@chemistwarehouse.com.au use unsubscribe link at the end of every email we send you.

#### Giving information to third parties

As well as sharing your information with our group companies and giving our service providers information to help us provide our products and services to you, we may give your information to others (third parties) in the following circumstances.

  1. _If we are selling any business or assets, in which case we may give your personal information to the prospective buyer of such business or asset._
  2. _If we, or most of our assets, are taken over by a third party (as your personal information may be one of those assets)._
  3. _If we have to provide or share your personal information in order to:_
    1. _meet any legal obligation or a request from a court or the police;_
    2. _enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or_
    3. _protect the rights, property, or safety of us, our customers or others._

This may involve sharing information for the purposes of preventing fraud, carrying out identity and age-related checks, and reducing credit risks, and contacting prescribers when our pharmacist becomes aware of significant medical issues arising in connection with a repeat prescription.

Our website may contain links to third parties’ websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those websites.

**This privacy policy applies only to personal information we collect from you through our website or in our dealings with you. We recommend that you check our cookie policies to help you understand how you can control sharing your personal information.**

**Cross Border Disclosure**

Personal Information may be disclosed to our service providers, including service providers which are located outside of Australia for the purpose of us providing services and marketing material to you. Except in some circumstances where we may rely on an exemption under the Act or other law, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that that the privacy of your Personal Information is addressed in any service agreement with our service providers.

#### Security

The security of your personal information is very important to us, and we take all appropriate security measures (including physical, electronic and procedural measures) to help protect it from being seen or shared by people or organisations not authorized to receive it. Personal Electronic Information provided to Chemiswarehouse.com.au will be stored on servers located in Australia. Physical copies of Personal Information provided may be kept in storage rooms with restricted access. When sending your personal information to a third party in order to provide goods or services you have ordered through our website, we will use reasonable ways of keeping your personal information secure.

Despite this commitment, we will not be liable if information transmitted over the internet is revealed, altered or misused. Any Information sent to us via the Internet is sent at your own risk. ChemistWarehouse.com.au shall not be held accountable for the privacy practices of other websites which appear as links on our website or to links to our websites from other websites. ChemistWarehouse.com.au may contain links to other sites which may be located within or outside of Australia. This privacy policy does not apply to any sites which are not controlled or operated by us.

**How can ChemistWarehouse.com.au customers ensure the accuracy and rectification in regard to their Personal Information?**

When Personal Information is provided to us by you, you warrant that the Personal Information given is accurate, current and complete and undertake to maintain the accuracy, currency and completeness of the Information which we retain. You also warrant that you have authority to provide this Personal Information to us.

Registered customers can view and alter the Personal Information they have provided by logging in with their username and password and accessing their account information. The Personal Information we retain includes patient profiles, addresses, and past orders. Access to this Personal Information by our staff can only be performed by staff members with a secure password, with access only granted when required. Access to this Information is recorded by log files to track unauthorised access and modifications.

**Can ChemistWarehouse.com.au customers order with anonymity?**

As **ChemistWarehouse.com.au** requires a physical address to deliver parcels to and a signature on delivery, anonymity cannot be assured. Customers may use a pseudonym for the purpose of registering for marketing information only.

**How can ChemistWarehouse.com.au customers' information be removed from our database?**

If at any stage a **ChemistWarehouse.com.au** customer would like their Personal Information removed from our database, we require an email with the username, password and identifying information and the customers file will be deleted from our records. Please send to: [**info@chemistwarehouse.com.au**](mailto:info@chemistwarehouse.com.au)

#### Your right to see your health record

You can ask us in writing for a copy of all the personal information we hold about you. We will endeavor to respond to your request within reasonable time. You will need to give enough information for our staff to identify you (for example, your full name, address and date of birth). You will need to provide ID (for example, your passport, full driving license or credit card or debit card) before any information can be released to you.

If you think any information we hold about you is incorrect, please let us know at [info@chemistwarehouse.com.au](mailto:info@chemistwarehouse.com.au)

If you have any questions, contact us by visiting [https://www.chemistwarehouse.com.au](https://www.chemistwarehouse.com.au/)

#### What Are COOKIES

When you visit our site we may use cookies and other technologies to automatically collect the following information however not limited to:

  1. _Technical information, including your IP address, your login information, browser type and version, device identifier, location and time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, page response times, and download errors;_
  2. _Information about your visit, including the websites you visit before and after our site and products you viewed or searched for;_
  3. _Length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page._

Also, emails that we send as part of our marketing programs use clear gifs (web beacons). These tell us whether the email has been opened. Web beacons can be turned off by not “enabling images” in an email.

A cookie is a piece of data that a website places on your browser when you visit the website. A cookie can store a range of information.

We use cookies and other automated means to help you navigate our website efficiently and to perform certain functions, including site traffic analytics and security and fraud prevention. Cookies may also recognize you on your next login, and offer you content and advertising tailored to your preferences and interests. Cookies do not compromise the security of a website.

We use various technologies to collect this information, including cookies and web beacons, and when we say “cookies” we mean all of these technologies. Note that disabling some cookie categories may impact your experience of our site.

You can also delete cookies that have already been set. You can opt out of cookies by visiting <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**Cookie Domain**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---  
  
**.chemistwarehouse.com.au**

| 

All Cookies are leveraged to provide site functionality, analytics and advertising and profiling to ensure you get the best experience possible  
  
Below is the list of third-party-service providers we use who can leave cookies to be able to work for their intended purposes. Should you have any queries regarding cookies used by them and what information they collect and why please visit respective cookie policy page links provided below.

**Provider** | **Purpose/Service provided** | **Cookie policy page**  
---|---|---  
**Criteo** | Digital Marketing/Targeting/Profiling | <https://www.criteo.com/privacy/>  
**Optimizely** | Web Optimization, AB testing/personalization | <https://www.optimizely.com/anz/privacy/>  
**Facebook** | Digital Marketing/Targeting/ Profiling/Analytics | [https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies)  
**Bazaarvoice** | Product Reviews | <https://www.bazaarvoice.com/legal/privacy-policy/>  
**Doubleclick** | Digital Marketing/Targeting/Profiling/Analytics | <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>  
**Newrelic** | Site performance monitoring | <https://newrelic.com/>  
**Bing** | Marketing/Analytics | [https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement/](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement)  
**Google Analytics** | Digital Marketing/Targeting | <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>  
**SLI System** | Site Search | <https://www.sli-systems.com.au/>  
**Add This** | Social Sharing in Catalogue | <https://www.addthis.com/privacy/terms-of-service/>  
**Lasoo** | Catalogue | [https://www.lasoo.com.au](https://www.lasoo.com.au/)  
**YouTube** | Marketing/product video content | <https://policies.google.com/>  
**Visa** | Payment Gateway | [https://www.visa.com.au](https://www.visa.com.au/)  
**Rakuten (link share)** | Digital Marketing/Targeting | <https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-au/legal-notices/services-privacy-policy>  
**PayPal** | Payment gateway | <https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full#2>  
**Braintree** | Payment Gateway | <https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full#2>  
**Cheetah Digital** | Email marketing | <http://marketing.cheetahdigital.com/privacy-policy/>  
**Adyen** | Payment Gateway | <https://www.adyen.com/>  
**Barilliance** | Email marketing, profiling | <https://www.barilliance.com/privacy-policy/>  
**Stratosphere** | Media marketing | [https://www.stratosphereagency.com](https://www.stratosphereagency.com/)  
**Google Display Network** | Digital Marketing/Targeting | <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>  

HOW YOU CAN MANAGE COOKIES?

If you don’t want to receive cookies, you can modify your browser setting, so that it notifies you when cookies are sent to it, or you can refuse cookies altogether. You can also delete cookies that have already been set.

The help function within your browser should tell you how to do this.

Alternatively, you may wish to visit www.aboutcookies.org, which contains comprehensive information on how to refine or remove cookies on a wide variety of desktop browsers.

**_Changes to this privacy policy_**

This policy was last updated on 28-03-2019.
